Evan Bruce

Web Developer

Evan Bruce

3417 Claybridge dr Bloomington, IN 47401 812-340-5389

Email: evanbruce19@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-bruce-896043138/

Github: https://github.com/evanbruce38

Portfolio: https://evanbruce38.github.io/react-portfolio/

Summary

Front-end web developer leveraging sales background to build a more interactive user experience on the web. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Miami, with newly developed skills in Javascript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, and SQL. Problem-solver with a hard-nosed attitude perfect for completing difficult assignments and projects. Excited to leverage my skills as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team to build better experiences on the web.

Experience

Elite Source Recruiting / Technical Recruiter

January 2022 - June 2022, Tampa, FL

Reached out to potential candidates via linkedin recruiter and CareerBuilder. Called candidates to discuss their qualifications and idel opportunities. Helped candidates through interview process to place into tech based roles.

Sunbelt Staffing / Account Manager

March 2021 - January 2022, Tampa FL

Cold called candidates to pitch school based healthcare positions. Managed candidates through bullhorn CRM. Cold called school districts to discuss their staffing needs and how sunbelt can assist. Negotiated placement deals with school districts.

Florida Financial Advisors / Junior Financial Consultant

May 2020 - February 2021, Tampa FL

Cold called potential clients using hubspot and linkedin. Established relationships with clients through phone calls and meetings over zoom. Helped clients to analyze their current portfolios and how to achieve their financial goals.

Certifications

Financial

SIE, Series 6, Series 65, and Florida 2-14 life insurance.

Tech

University of Miami Coding Bootcamp

Education

University of Miami Bootcamps / Coding Certificate

June 2022 - November 2022, Miami FL

University of Mississippi / Managerial Finance

August 2015 - May 2020, Oxford MS

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Web APIs

Node.js

Express.js

SQL

MySQL

NoSQL

React

Projects

DevConnect

A social media platform for developers to connect and share their projects with one another. DevConnect is like github, linkedin, and facebook all rolled into one application. This project was created using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, Handlebars, and SQL.

Github: https://github.com/evanbruce38/dev-connect-portfolio-sharing

Link: https://dev-connect-portfolio-sharing.herokuapp.com/

Find A K-9

An application created to allow users to search for a K-9 picture based on their breed. The application uses a dog picture web API to provide photos of different breeds. This application uses HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and web based API.

Github: https://github.com/evanbruce38/Find-a-K-9

Link: https://evanbruce38.github.io/Find-a-K-9/

Weather Dashboard

This application uses a live weather API to allow users to search for current weather conditions by city. This application uses HTML, CSS, and javascript, along with the weather API.

Github:

https://github.com/evanbruce38/Challenge-6-Weather-Dashboard

Link: https://evanbruce38.github.io/Challenge-6-Weather-Dashboard/

Note Taker

An application that allows a user to write and save notes in JSON to the application. This app was created using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Express to tie together the front and back end..

Github: https://github.com/evanbruce38/Note-Taker

Link: https://immense-wave-00583.herokuapp.com/

Password Generator

An application that lets a user input criteria for the type of password they would like to be generated that then creates a password structured to follow a user's specifications. This project was created using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Github: https://github.com/evanbruce38/Password-Generator

Link: https://evanbruce38.github.io/Password-Generator/